# Jon Connor, Dublin, Ireland. 087 1374592

## ionconnor@live.ie

# **Summary**

Motivated Software Tester with 7 years of progressive experience in the Software Testing industry. Offering expertise in manual and automation testing, planning, and reviewing with an aptitude in requirements gathering. Energetic self-starter and team builder able to navigate high-stress situations and achieve goals on time.

## **Current Certification**

- ISTQB BCS Certified Agile Tester Extension (FLA)
- ISTQB BCS Certified Tester Foundation Level (ISEB-SWT2)
- City & Guilds Level 2 Software Testing (7540-12-012)
- Microsoft Technical Associate Database Fundamentals (98-364)

## **Key Skills**

- Review, understand & interpret Business Requirements
- Testing Software to ensure compliance with Business Requirements
- JIRA to plan and track features and tasks, raise and track defects
- Zephyr Scale to write test cases and test plans
- UI Automation testing with Java, Selenium and Cucumber
- Maintaining an automated framework using GIT
- Advocating for the end user throughout the development

- Work with developers to achieve resolution of defects
- Foundation level Knowledge of HTML & CSS, JavaScript, SQL
- Azure Dev Ops to plan and track features, create tests, and test plans, record test execution and record, track defects
- Conduct functional tests using black box techniques
- Testing with emulators & VM ware
- Using Jenkins to schedule runs and produce metrics/reports
- Communicating effectively with stakeholders and vendors to keep projects on track

#### Experience

# Contract QA Analyst, Pexlify, Dublin

June 2022 – present

Pexlify are a certified partner of Salesforce and are a recommended developer of Salesforce customisation for Salesforce customers. Currently working on a Salesforce Financial Services cloud implementation for Ruffer PLC. This is an agile project and I manually test stories during each sprint, report any bugs or issues in Jira and verify fixes have been implemented correctly. Identifying test cases and stories to use for regression testing as the sprints progress. Implementing these test cases into a cucumber framework (UI). Assisting Engagement Manager and Business Analyst to 'demo' sprint deliverables and produce a user guide.

#### Contract QA Analyst, The Central Bank of Ireland, Dublin (Employed via Expleo Group)

June 2021 – June 2022

Working on the 'Fitness and Probity' agile project to bring a paper application process to a fully online front-end webbased application, integrated with a client (Bank) side CRM.

Prepare data sheets for use with UFT automation testing for regression. Request keywords for new features and ensure they are developed correctly and function in the data sheets.

Attend and participate in agile ceremonies - daily stand-up's, fortnightly sprint reviews, sprint retrospectives, backlog grooming sessions, estimation sessions, three amigo's sessions.

Prepare test cases, log static defects when conflicts are identified between acceptance criteria and requirements documentation. Carry out test execution and log defects, retest, and close fixed issues. Assist with UAT and investigate UAT defects.

## Contract QA Engineer, SAP Ariba, Dublin (Employed via Manpower Ireland)

August 2020 - June 2021

Working in the QA department of the localisation team. Reviewing strings for translatability by flagging and logging localisation issues in JIRA. Using a Selenium/Java/Jenkins/Git framework to update, fix or create new scripts. The automated scripts capture screen shots of the strings and aid translation by providing context to the strings. After translation, ensuring the functionality of the translated screens is intact by running the scripts in the localised languages. Using JIRA to investigate new features for new strings and deciding to either update existing scripts or create new ones. Increased the overnight pass rates from 30% to 75% by using pre-created events in the scripts rather than creating the event from scratch.

## Contract Software Tester, Accounting Technicians Ireland, Dublin 2

April 2018 – March 2020

Successfully implemented an assessment module in the new CRM software package by identifying missing requirements in the developer's specifications from the test cases I wrote for coverage of the business rules. Working on a membership module to add to the CRM and enhancing an existing apprentice module to accommodate new business vision and requirements. Using cucumber and gherkin to develop and produce business requirements for these new modules.

#### **Software Tester, Interactive Services, Dublin 15**

May 2017 – April 2018

Responsible for the testing within a development team that specializes in the localization of e-learning courses for the financial services sectors. There was no formal test plan, so I developed and implemented a test charter, so all software released was at an acceptable standard. Client fixes for functionality dropped dramatically. Upskilled in HTML/CSS and GIT so that I could fix minor text and graphics issues. The Project Manager would receive minor issues from client and assign to me to fix. I would then assign back to Project Manager to keep independence in the fix and verify bug cycle. This freed up programmers to do more urgent and important tasks in the project.

## Warehouse Tester, Actavo (In Home Division), Dublin 12

August 2016 - April 2017

Tested set top boxes (SKY TV) to confirm faulty using a series of manual tests. Updated the stock on the company's system and organised return to the client. By asking the business leaders and managers questions about the high level of set top boxes that were incorrectly assigned as faulty. I could see the negative impact it had on the business. I created a simple spreadsheet that recorded every set top box I tested along with Engineer ID, Team, Team Manager and Area Manager. I was then able to identify which Engineers, Teams, Managers and Area Managers were having issues diagnosing faulty set top boxes. Extra training was arranged, and the non-faulty boxes returned as faulty steadily dropped to an acceptable level.

# **Temporary Software Tester, Interactive Services, Dublin 15**

October 2015 - August 2016

Obtained a 4-week work placement via ETB training course. Was kept on in a temporary basis testing various types of custom E-Learning solutions for Fortune 500 companies such as Coca Cola, Deloitte, Facebook, Hershey, LinkedIn, Morgan Stanley, United Airlines, VISA and Walmart. Regression testing, checking functionality, localization testing, and working on a new template to ensure functionality and display was consistent over numerous browsers, devices and OS using emulators and the actual devices.

#### Pre-2015

Emissions testing roles from 2002 to 2015 and from 1990 to 2002, in a quality assurance/quality control role for a manufacturer of adhesive papers and vinyl.

#### **Education**

# St Bede's RC College, Manchester

1983 - 1990

- 4 GCE A- Level: Pure Mathematics with Mechanics, Physics, Chemistry & General Studies
- 8 GCSE including English & Mathematics

#### **Further information**

LinkedIn: <a href="www.linkedin.com/in/jonconnordublin">www.linkedin.com/in/jonconnordublin</a>
GitHub: <a href="https://jonconnorati.github.io/JonConnor/">https://jonconnorati.github.io/JonConnor/</a>